United Automobile, Aerospace and Agricultural Implement Workers of America Workers Local 930; Records apap038
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
United Automobile Aerospace And Agricultural Implement Workers of America Local 930 Records1944-1966, 1968, 1970-1989
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
United Automobile Aerospace And Agricultural Implement Workers Of America Local 930
apap038
2 cubic ft.
Records of UAW Local 930 which represented the Ford Motors plant in Green Island, NY.
Acquisition Information
All items in this manuscript group were donated to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, by Local 930 of the United Automobile, Aerospace and Agricultural Implement Workers of America, on October 24, 1989.
Organizational Sketch
UAW Local 930 was chartered on August 7, 1941. The Ford Motors plant at Green Island, New York, produced automobile parts that were shipped to Ford assembly plants in the United States and Canada. During the last twenty years of operation, the plant produced leaf springs, radiators and heater cores. The Ford plant closed in December 1988 and Local 930 in October 1989.
Scope and Contents
Contains minutes, 1944–66, 1975–89; correspondence, 1971–88; newsletters, 1971–72, 1984–85; contracts, 1961, 1970–87; constitutions and by–laws, 1964, 1974–83; photographs, 1944, ca. 1985; audio tapes, 1985; a published history, 1988; and memorabilia, 1968, 1982–88. Also contains the records of the UAW New York Capital Area Political Action Committee, 1971, 1977–87.
Access
Access to this record group is unrestricted.
Arrangement of the Collection
This collection has no series.
Labor; Albany, New York; Automobile industry workers -- Labor unions; Labor unions -- New York (State) -- Green Island.; Correspondence; Minutes; Contracts; Bylaws; United Automobile, Aerospace, and Agricultural Implement Workers of America -- Local 930 (Green Island, N.Y.); Ford Motor Company
- Minutes, 1944-1966; 1975-1981; 1985-1989; 1
  - Executive Board Meeting Minutes, 1944-1958 (Box 1 (1-Minutes), Folder 1)
  - Membership Meeting Minutes, 1946-1955 (Box 1 (1-Minutes), Folder 2)
  - Membership Meeting Minutes, 1955-1959 (Box 1 (1-Minutes), Folder 3)
  - Executive Board and Membership Meeting Minutes, 1959-1963 (Box 1 (1-Minutes), Folder 4)
  - Executive Board and Membership Meeting Minutes, 1963-1966 (Box 1 (1-Minutes), Folder 5)
  - Executive Board and Membership Meeting Minutes, 1975-1978 (Box 1 (1-Minutes), Folder 6)
  - Executive Board and Membership Meeting Minutes, 1978-1981 (Box 1 (1-Minutes), Folder 7)
  - Executive Board and Membership Meeting Minutes, 1985-1989 (Box 1 (1-Minutes), Folder 8)
- Correspondence, 1971-1974; 1977-1988; 2
  - Correspondence, 1971-1974; 1977-1979 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence), Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1980-1983 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence), Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1984-1988 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence), Folder 3)
- Subject Files, 1944; 1961; 1964; 1968; 1970-1977; 1979-1988; 3
  - Agreements Between UAW 930 and Ford Motor Company Green Island Plant, 1979; 1987 (Box 1 (3-Subject Files), Folder 1)
  - Agreements Between UAW and Ford, 1961; 1970 (Box 1 (3-Subject Files), Folder 2)
  - Agreements Between UAW and Ford, 1973 (Box 1 (3-Subject Files), Folder 3)
  - Agreements Between UAW and Ford, 1976 (Box 1 (3-Subject Files), Folder 4)
  - Agreements Between UAW and Ford, 1979 (Box 1 (3-Subject Files), Folder 5)
  - Agreements Between UAW and Ford, 1982 (Box 1 (3-Subject Files), Folder 6)
  - Agreements Between UAW and Ford, 1984 (Box 1 (3-Subject Files), Folder 7)
  - Agreements Between UAW and Ford, 1987 (Box 1 (3-Subject Files), Folder 8)
  - Audiotape--Meeting of UAW Local 845, 1985 (Box 1 (3-Subject Files), Folder 9)
  - By-Laws of National Ford Council, 1974; 1983 (Box 1 (3-Subject Files), Folder 10)
  - By-Laws of UAW Local 930, 1964 (Box 1 (3-Subject Files), Folder 11)
  - Bulletin Board Notices, 1973 (Box 1 (3-Subject Files), Folder 12)
  - Constitutions of International Union, UAW, 1974; 1977; 1980; 1983 (Box 1 (3-Subject Files), Folder 13)
  - Convention Appeals Committee-Minutes, 1984 (Box 1 (3-Subject Files), Folder 14)
  - Employee Involving Committee (EI), 1981-1982; 1977; 1980; 1983 (Box 1 (3-Subject Files), Folder 15)
  - Green Island Plant: 65 Years of Pride, 1988 (Box 1 (3-Subject Files), Folder 16)
  - Grievances, 1973; 1983-1984 (Box 1 (3-Subject Files), Folder 17)
  - Memorabilia, 1968; 1975; 1980-1985; 1988 (Box 1 (3-Subject Files), Folder 18)
  - Newsletters of UAW Local 930, 1971-1972; 1983-1987 (Box 1 (3-Subject Files), Folder 19)
  - Open Letter to All Ford Stockholders--Leaflet by UAW 930, 1986 (Box 2 (3-Subject Files), Folder 1)
  - Photographs--CIO and New York State Industrial Union Council Conventions, 1944 (Box 2 (3-Subject Files), Folder 2)
  - Protest of UAW 930 Election, 1971 (Box 2 (3-Subject Files), Folder 3)
  - Retirees' Banquets, 1981-1987 (Box 2 (3-Subject Files), Folder 4)
  - Skilled Trades Meeting Minutes, 1983-1984 (Box 2 (3-Subject Files), Folder 5)
  - Strike of 1976, 1976-1977 (Box 2 (3-Subject Files), Folder 6)
  - Transcript of Meeting, 1985 (Box 2 (3-Subject Files), Folder 7)
  - Transfer Agreement--Green Island Plant Climate Control Division, 1983 (Box 2 (3-Subject Files), Folder 8)
  - UAW Song Book, 1975 (Box 2 (3-Subject Files), Folder 9)
- United Auto Workers New York Capital Area Action Council Records, 1971; 1977-1978; 1981-1982; 1987; 4
  - By-Laws, 1971; 1977 (Box 2 (4-United Auto Workers New York Capital Area Action C), Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, 1977-1978; 1981-1982; 1987 (Box 2 (4-United Auto Workers New York Capital Area Action C), Folder 11)
  - Membership List, 1975 (Box 2 (4-United Auto Workers New York Capital Area Action C), Folder 12)